Liu, Teng-Yuan (Shuk Liu)

<u>biz.shuk@gmail.com</u>, Skype: initialshuk <u>Linkedin</u>, TW (886) 0902-398-163

Summary last updated: 2021-09-26

A engineer around 8-10 yrs experience looks for good opportunities/interesting challenges/big project scale. I'm capable as full-stack engineer, but has more strength on backend. Also, having some management experience, and cross-team communication skills(Both internal/external team/cross-region).

Skills

Certificate: AWS - Solution Architect - associate (2018/08), TOEIC: 830(2019/01)

Language: Golang(Gin), Java (Spring Boot, MVC, Batch, Data), js(Reactjs, Redux), AWS(TF, CF), Bash, SQL PHP, Perl, HTML5/CSS (SASS),

Server as a admin: Linux, Git, Nginx, Docker, Jenkins, Apache HTTP

Server as a user: Mysql(schema design), ElasticSearch, Mongo, Gitlab-CI, Rundeck, Jenkins

Concept: SOLID, Design Pattern, CI/CD, MVC, Network, RWD, Cache, HA, Scalability, BDD, Agile, Lean, Scrum Micro-service, Platform design. OAuth2

Work Experience

Tech Lead + Senior Engineer | Innova Solutions | Songshan, TW

 $2017/02 \sim 2022/09$

Cloud solution provider. In this branch, it's BOT for Change Health Care(CHC) in U.S. healthcare industry

- Work on AWS, Golang, Java (Spring Boot, MVC, Batch, Data), ElasticSearch, Reactis, Scrum. Manage cross-functional Scrum team(5p) in Taipei. Cross-regional/team communication, Production support
- Manage 5-8p (including QA) and lead another re-org team to form and catch up US teams
- As an interviewer for Senior and Lead level, around 30 rounds and found qualified candidates.
- Integrating of Enterprise Solution in CHC and architect User Engagement process (AWS Pinpoint)
- Traversed whole stack of legacy system and migrated some to new cloud architecture(not app) successfully.
- Scan and resolve security issues diagnosed by Fortify. (Email unsubscribe with JWT, KMS with jenkins CI)
- Create frameworks for Java(Lambda, Event Annotation, Spring Secret Manager plugin) Go(EventBus).
- Debug CPU consumption through jstack jstat jmap.
- Construct persistent file process architecture to process batch files and other massive processing with Async.

Cloud Engineer | Shanghai Droi Tech Co. Ltd. | Taipei 101, TW

2015/07 - 2016/05

Internet company, 500+ people, from device hardware to backend as a cloud application solution (e.g. parse.com)

- Worked on Bash, Lua, Linux, Nginx, Docker, Jenkins, Ansible, Kubenetes, Mongo, PostgreSQL.
- Model "Backend As A Service" arch including app commit flow and integrate with Jenkins toward Kubernetes.
- End to end test framework on the platform, including syntax check, api detected, and request profiling.
- Cli tool to make linear version control, let user manage their own code simply.

Game and BI developer | Gamesofa Inc. | Taipei, TW

2012/11 - 2015/04

Online Game company, 200 people, self-made games including Mahjong, Poker, FPS, and RPG

- Worked on LAMP, Perl, HTML5, Javascript, AngularJS, CSS, Memcache, A/B testing.
- Get requirements from PM, check the scope in each small sprint. Eventually, collaborate with QA and delivery.
- Win8 App "Godgame big two" by HTML5, integrate billing services, interact with back-end, adjust UI.
- Responsible for "Godgame Texas Hold'em" events and features, e.g. Friend list across multiple games.
- Reduced Omaha game rule execution time with probability.
- Collaborated with data analysis to develop flexible survey system (region-based) to control how it present
- Built data analyzing system showing user retention rate, payment and activated situations with selected group. It's easy for product manager and marketing specialist. And we may do some A/B testing for groups of user.
- Refactor customer service system and maintain existing systems.

Web developer | National Central University | Jongli, Taiwan

2010/03-2011/06

Setup LAMP websites, bypass library system for ebook search, saving \$20000 at least and maintaining fee

Education

- M.S. in CS, National Central University, Jongli , Taiwan, 2009.09-2011.06, June. (Java, PHP)
- B.S. in CS, National Dong-Hua University, Hualien, Taiwan, 2004.09-2009.06, Jan. (C, C++, PHP)